Subtitle Provide by dramacool.asia Translator [Admin.@YNG]
تم توفير الترجمة بواسطة مترجم dramacool.asia [Admin.@YNG]
Be careful climbing the ladder.
كن حذرا عند تسلق السلم.
Slow down, slow down.
أبطئ، أبطئ.
Father really wants me to marry that useless Li Ling?
هل يريد والدي حقًا أن أتزوج من تلك لي لينغ عديمة الفائدة؟
How dare you!
كيف تجرؤ!
It's your father's decision.
هذا قرار والدك.
You must obey.
يجب عليك أن تطيع.
No questioning allowed.
لا يسمح بالاستجواب.
But...
لكن...
But what?
ولكن ماذا؟
Do you really dislike him?
هل تكرهه حقا؟
Not really.
ليس حقيقيًا.
It's just...
إنه فقط...
My daughter,
ابنتي
Do you truly not understand,
هل حقا لا تفهم؟
or are you just pretending in front of me?
أم أنك تتظاهر فقط أمامي؟
I'm talking about the Li family's pearl business.
أنا أتحدث عن تجارة اللؤلؤ لعائلة لي.
Do you think if they hand over the Li family,
هل تعتقد أنه إذا سلموا عائلة لي،
we can fully control everything?
هل يمكننا السيطرة على كل شيء بشكل كامل؟
Especially their trade route.
وخاصة طريقهم التجاري.
A list alone is useless.
القائمة وحدها لا فائدة منها.
Without the Li family's involvement,
بدون تدخل عائلة لي،
they won't do business with us.
لن يقوموا بإجراء أي أعمال تجارية معنا.
Think again.
فكر مرة أخرى.
But what if you become the Li family's daughter-in-law?
ولكن ماذا لو أصبحتِ زوجة ابن عائلة لي؟
Zhang Ji,
تشانغ جي,
you should thank Li Ling.
ينبغي عليك أن تشكر لي لينغ.
I told you before,
لقد قلت لك من قبل،
your last mission was your final chance.
مهمتك الأخيرة كانت فرصتك الأخيرة.
You messed it up completely.
لقد أفسدت الأمر تماما.
If Li Ling didn't want to marry you,
إذا لم ترغب لي لينغ في الزواج منك،
I...
أنا...
Daughter,
بنت،
I know you feel wronged.
أعرف أنك تشعر بالظلم.
But think carefully.
ولكن فكر جيدا.
If we truly
إذا كنا حقا
gain control of the Li family's wealth,
السيطرة على ثروة عائلة لي،
the appetite of those noble families in the capital
شهية تلك العائلات النبيلة في العاصمة
will finally be satisfied.
وسوف تكون راضيا في النهاية.
Your brother
أخوك
will have a better life.
سيكون لدي حياة أفضل.
I understand, Father.
انا أفهم يا أبي.
If this succeeds,
إذا نجح هذا،
then a mother's status is elevated by her daughter's marriage.
ثم ترتفع مكانة الأم بزواج ابنتها.
Your mother's memorial tablet
لوحة تذكارية لوالدتك
can naturally
يمكن بطبيعة الحال
be placed in our Zhang family ancestral hall.
سيتم وضعها في قاعة أسلاف عائلة تشانغ.
Thank you, Father.
شكرا لك يا أبي.
Congratulations!
مبروك!
Madam Huang, you're too kind.
السيدة هوانغ، أنت لطيفة للغاية.
Steward, greet the guests.
أيها المضيف، استقبل الضيوف.
Alright, alright.
حسناً حسناً.
Congratulations!
مبروك!
Please come inside.
من فضلك ادخل إلى الداخل.
Miss has still entrusted herself to the wrong person.
لا تزال السيدة قد سلمت نفسها للشخص الخطأ.
Li Ling is so ungrateful.
لي لينغ غير ممتنة للغاية.
Stop calling him young master.
توقف عن مناداته بالسيد الشاب.
He married the governor's daughter,
تزوج ابنة الحاكم،
but he could still marry Miss Rong'er.
لكن لا يزال بإمكانه الزواج من الآنسة رونغ إير.
Ah!
اه!
What did you say?
ماذا قلت؟
Please calm down, madam.
من فضلك اهدأي سيدتي.
Ouch.
آخ.
The tasks Miss and Young Master assigned
المهام الموكلة إلى الآنسة والسيد الشاب
we still have to do well.
لا زال يتعين علينا أن نبذل جهدا جيدا.
Hurry up and go.
اسرع واذهب.
Go quickly.
اذهب بسرعة.
Woguan Ceremony (a traditional wedding ritual)
حفل ووجوان (طقوس الزفاف التقليدية)
Duixi Ceremony (a traditional wedding ritual)
حفل دويكسي (طقوس الزفاف التقليدية)
Tonglao Ceremony (a traditional wedding ritual)
حفل تونغلاو (طقوس الزفاف التقليدية)
Hejin Ceremony (a traditional wedding ritual)
حفل هيجين (طقوس الزفاف التقليدية)
Let me ask you,
دعني اسألك
If one day you leave Hepu,
إذا غادرت هيبو يومًا ما،
where would you most want to go?
أين تريد أن تذهب أكثر؟
To the north, I think.
إلى الشمال، كما أعتقد.
I want to see the snow in the north.
أريد أن أرى الثلوج في الشمال.
It rarely snows in Hepu.
نادرًا ما تتساقط الثلوج في هيبو.
I've never seen snow before.
لم أرى الثلج من قبل .
Alright.
على ما يرام.
Then, after we get married,
ثم بعد أن نتزوج،
I'll take you there.
سوف آخذك إلى هناك.
We'll see all the snow in the north.
سوف نرى كل الثلوج في الشمال.
I know, I know.
أنا أعلم، أنا أعلم.
Peishou Ceremony (a traditional wedding ritual)
حفل بيشو (طقوس الزفاف التقليدية)
Jieying Ceremony (a traditional wedding ritual)
حفل جي يينغ (طقوس الزفاف التقليدية)
The ceremony is complete.
تم الانتهاء من الحفل.
Escort them to the bridal chamber.
اصطحبهم إلى غرفة الزفاف.
May you have a long and happy marriage.
أتمنى لك زواجًا طويلًا وسعيدًا.
They say a night of spring is worth a thousand pieces of gold.
يقولون أن ليلة الربيع تساوي ألف قطعة من الذهب.
But I feel in your eyes,
ولكنني أشعر في عينيك،
tonight isn't worth a penny.
الليلة لا تساوي فلسا واحدا.
Listen to yourself.
استمع إلى نفسك.
I've been lying here for ages.
لقد كنت مستلقيا هنا لسنوات.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Me?
أنا؟
Why are you staring?
لماذا تحدق؟
I'm not feeling well.
أنا لا أشعر بأنني على ما يرام.
I can't move easily.
لا أستطيع التحرك بسهولة.
Fine.
بخير.
Then I'll do it.
ثم سأفعل ذلك.
Oh!
أوه!
The sky over Hepu
السماء فوق هيبو
hasn't seen snow in years.
لم يرى الثلوج منذ سنوات.
This is auspicious snow.
هذا هو الثلج الميمون.
It foretells
إنه يتنبأ
Li Ling and Zhang Ji
لي لينغ وتشانغ جي
will surely bring blessings to Hepu.
سوف يجلب البركات إلى هيبو بالتأكيد.
Since fate has decided,
منذ أن قرر القدر،
you two are destined to be apart.
من المقدر لكما أن تكونا منفصلين.
Why be sad about it?
لماذا تحزن بشأن ذلك؟
Master Zhang,
السيد تشانغ،
will you marry me?
هل ستتزوجني؟
That's it?
هذا كل شيء؟
Go on.
إستمر.
Li Ling,
لي لينغ,
Why aren't you pretending anymore?
لماذا لم تعد تتظاهر؟
You fooled my father,
لقد خدعت والدي
but can you fool me?
ولكن هل تستطيع أن تخدعني؟
You...
أنت...
I...
أنا...
Do we have a choice?
هل لدينا خيار؟
If Li Ling wasn't marrying you,
إذا لم يكن لي لينغ يتزوجك،
I...
أنا...
We're just people hurt by the governor.
نحن مجرد أشخاص تأذوا من قبل المحافظ.
All of us.
كلنا.
Since none of us have a choice,
وبما أنه ليس لدى أي منا خيار،
why hurt each other?
لماذا نؤذي بعضنا البعض؟
If we get married,
إذا تزوجنا،
at least we'll live a bit longer.
على الأقل سوف نعيش لفترة أطول قليلا.
Isn't that right?
أليس هذا صحيحا؟
Husband,
زوج،
I think you're right.
أعتقد أنك على حق.
Greetings, Father-in-law.
تحياتي، حمي.
Greetings, Father.
تحياتي لك يا أبي.
Daughter.
بنت.
Good son-in-law.
صهر جيد.
Come, come.
تعال، تعال.
I have happy news to announce.
لدي أخبار سعيدة أريد أن أعلنها.
Soon,
قريباً،
I will marry
سأتزوج
Miss Jia Rong'er.
السيدة جيا رونغ إير.
Congratulations, Father!
مبروك يا أبي!
With this,
مع هذا،
our governor's residence
مقر إقامة حاكمنا
will have double happiness.
سيكون لدي سعادة مضاعفة.
Congratulations, Father-in-law.
ألف مبروك يا حمي.
Congratulations, Miss Jia.
مبروك يا آنسة جيا.
Miss Jia,
الآنسة جيا،
after my mother and mistress passed away,
بعد وفاة والدتي وسيدتي،
Father has been busy with official duties.
كان الأب مشغولاً بواجباته الرسمية.
He never remarried.
ولم يتزوج مرة أخرى.
I never thought Miss Jia
لم أكن أعتقد أبدًا أن الآنسة جيا
would marry my father.
سوف اتزوج والدي.
From now on,
من الآن فصاعدا،
please take care of Father.
من فضلك اعتني بأبيك.
Once you are officially married,
بمجرد زواجك رسميًا،
I'll call you
سأتصل بك
Mother.
الأم.
Once the Central Plains trade route is open,
بمجرد فتح طريق التجارة في السهول الوسطى،
the Zhang, Jia, and Li families will be united.
سيتم توحيد عائلات تشانغ وجيا ولي.
Then Hepu
ثم هيبو
will belong to the Zhang family.
سوف تنتمي إلى عائلة تشانغ.
Daughter,
بنت،
this is your husband,
هذا زوجك
and the list from Miss Jia.
والقائمة من الآنسة جيا.
Set out immediately.
انطلق على الفور.
While investigating,
أثناء التحقيق،
do your best to keep the trade route
بذل قصارى جهدك للحفاظ على طريق التجارة
clear and unobstructed.
واضحة وغير معوقة.
for our use.
لاستخدامنا.
Yes, Father.
نعم يا أبي.
Xiao Hong,
شياو هونغ,
I'm hungry.
أنا جائع.
Bring some refreshments.
احضر بعض المرطبات.
Yes.
نعم.
Ouch.
آخ.
Seriously.
بجد.
Didn't I tell Kana to take you away first?
ألم أخبر كانا أن يأخذك بعيدًا أولاً؟
Why did you come to the Governor's residence?
لماذا أتيت إلى منزل المحافظ؟
And you're marrying that old bastard?
و هل ستتزوجين هذا الرجل العجوز؟
Hurry up and leave.
اسرع واذهب.
Go, quickly.
اذهب بسرعة.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Is it proper for the new son-in-law to speak of his father-in-law like that?
هل يليق بالصهر الجديد أن يتكلم عن حميه بهذا الشكل؟
That's not appropriate, is it?
هذا ليس مناسبا، أليس كذلك؟
No, madam.
لا سيدتي.
Stop teasing me.
توقف عن مضايقتي.
I told you to leave first, I have my own way.
لقد طلبت منك المغادرة أولاً، لدي طريقتي الخاصة.
Your way is to marry Zhang Ji.
طريقتك هي الزواج من تشانغ جي.
Then...
ثم...
On your wedding night,
في ليلة زفافك،
I waited outside your bridal chamber all night.
لقد انتظرت خارج غرفة زفافك طوال الليل.
Do you know how I felt?
هل تعلم كيف شعرت؟
Since you can marry another woman,
بما أنه بإمكانك الزواج من امرأة أخرى،
why can't I marry another man?
لماذا لا أستطيع الزواج من رجل آخر؟
Is that really another man?
هل هذا حقا رجل آخر؟
That's an old man.
هذا رجل عجوز.
Do you know he's an old man?
هل تعلم أنه رجل عجوز؟
What can he give you?
ماذا يستطيع أن يعطيك؟
After your uncle and aunt passed away,
بعد وفاة عمك وعمتك،
I've taken care of you for so many years anyway.
لقد اعتنيت بك لسنوات عديدة على أي حال.
Changing my role
تغيير دوري
might not be so bad.
ربما لا يكون سيئا للغاية.
If I can't be your wife,
إذا لم أستطع أن أكون زوجتك،
being your mother is fine too.
أن تكون أمك فهذا أمر جيد أيضًا.
Rong'er
رونغ'ر
What I'm about to say
ما سأقوله الآن
might sound crazy to you.
ربما يبدو الأمر مجنونا بالنسبة لك.
But I've decided
ولكنني قررت
to tell you everything.
لأخبرك بكل شيء.
Actually, I've died once before.
في الواقع، لقد مت مرة واحدة من قبل.
In my previous life, I was killed by Wang Cheng.
في حياتي السابقة، قُتلت على يد وانغ تشنغ.
You were killed by Zhang Ji.
لقد قتلك تشانغ جي.
But I know behind all of this
ولكنني أعلم أن وراء كل هذا
is Zhang He.
هو تشانغ هي.
Heaven gave me a chance to live again.
لقد أعطتني السماء فرصة للعيش مرة أخرى.
But I know
ولكنني أعلم
the Li family's business still exists.
لا تزال أعمال عائلة لي موجودة.
The alliance between the Li and Jia families remains.
لا يزال التحالف بين عائلتي لي وجيا قائما.
He will never let me go.
لن يسمح لي بالرحيل أبدًا.
So I gave up the Li family's business.
لذلك تخليت عن أعمال عائلة لي.
I abandoned the trade route.
لقد تركت طريق التجارة.
I asked Kana to take you away first.
لقد طلبت من كانا أن يأخذك بعيدًا أولاً.
I just want you to live well.
أريد فقط أن تعيش حياة جيدة.
But Zhang He
لكن تشانغ هي
is truly cunning and deceitful.
إنه حقا ماكر ومخادع.
If I don't fully join his scheme,
إذا لم أنضم بشكل كامل إلى مخططه،
he will never trust me.
لن يثق بي أبدًا.
That's why I had no choice
لهذا السبب لم يكن لدي خيار
but to marry Zhang Ji to gain his trust.
لكن الزواج من تشانغ جي لكسب ثقته.
But then you showed up
ولكن بعد ذلك ظهرت
at the governor's mansion.
في قصر المحافظ.
You couldn't escape.
لم تتمكن من الهروب.
You should know, in our past lives,
يجب أن تعلم أنه في حياتنا الماضية،
you overheard their plot
لقد سمعت مؤامرتهم
and tried to warn me.
وحاول تحذيري.
That's why you were killed by them.
لهذا السبب قتلوك.
It's as if everything is repeating itself.
وكأن كل شيء يكرر نفسه.
I can't let this happen again.
لا أستطيع أن أسمح بحدوث هذا مرة أخرى.
When I came back to life, I thought
عندما عدت إلى الحياة، فكرت
in this life,
في هذه الحياة،
I will never let you down.
لن أخذلك أبدا.
I love you.
أحبك.
I want to marry you.
أريد الزواج منك.
I want to be with you forever.
أريد أن أكون معك إلى الأبد.
Do you know that?
هل تعلم ذلك؟
You said you liked me.
قلت أنك معجب بي.
You wanted to marry me.
لقد أردت الزواج مني.
I told you so much,
لقد قلت لك الكثير
but all you heard was
ولكن كل ما سمعته كان
"pain."
"ألم."
That's how I knew this wasn't a dream.
وهكذا عرفت أن هذا لم يكن حلما.
You said you wanted to marry me.
قلت أنك تريد الزواج مني.
I just knew
لقد عرفت للتو
you wouldn't believe what I said.
لن تصدق ما قلته.
I believe you.
واعتقد انكم.
I trust you.
أنا أثق بك.
But I can't let you
ولكن لا يمكنني أن أسمح لك
take risks alone anymore.
لا أتحمل المخاطر بمفردي بعد الآن.
Just think about it.
فقط فكر في الأمر.
I know
أنا أعرف
you and Kana
أنت وكانا
must be planning something.
يجب أن تخطط لشيء ما.
But Zhang He isn't so easily fooled.
لكن تشانغ هي ليس من السهل خداعه.
Even if you give him the trade route,
حتى لو أعطيته طريق التجارة،
he will still investigate.
سيستمر في التحقيق.
Even if Zhang Ji
حتى لو تشانغ جي
claims to be your wife, Li Ling,
يدعي أنه زوجتك، لي لينغ،
in everyone's eyes before,
في عيون الجميع من قبل،
only I, Jia Rong'er,
أنا فقط، جيا رونغ إير،
am your true wife.
أنا زوجتك الحقيقية.
So unless everything is foolproof,
لذا ما لم يكن كل شيء مضمونًا،
Zhang He won't let me go.
تشانغ لن يسمح لي بالذهاب.
I have to give him more leverage.
يجب أن أعطيه المزيد من النفوذ.
Only then will you be safer.
حينها فقط ستكون أكثر أمانا.
But you can't marry him.
ولكن لا يمكنك الزواج منه.
Zhang He stood guard outside your bridal chamber all night.
لقد وقف تشانغ هي حارسًا خارج غرفة زفافك طوال الليل.
If I don't give him more leverage,
إذا لم أعطيه المزيد من النفوذ،
all our efforts will be wasted.
كل جهودنا سوف تذهب سدى.
That old pervert.
هذا المنحرف العجوز.
Check carefully over there.
تأكد من ذلك بعناية.
Yes.
نعم.
Go quickly.
اذهب بسرعة.
He ordered the servants not to let you near me.
وأمر الخدم بعدم السماح لك بالاقتراب مني.
Rong'er
رونغ'ر
I want you to be my wife.
أريدك أن تكوني زوجتي.
Not my mother.
ليست أمي.
Wait for me.
الانتظار لي.
Hearing you say that
سماعك تقول ذلك
is enough for me.
هذا يكفيني.
Husband.
زوج.